hi if you've never cut hair before or if
you're a beginner
then this video is for you in this short
demonstration
i will show step by step how to cut boys
or men's hair with clippers
in the simplest way possible so by the
end of this video
you will know all the basic techniques
that can be applied to practically
every haircut feel free to leave your
comments or questions below
for this haircut you will need a pair of
sharp scissors
a comb a sprayer bottle and of course a
pair of clippers with safety guards
if you're cutting hair for the first
time i would recommend starting off with
a number four
guard today for this example haircut i'm
going to use a number three guard
start with the sides and back don't
forget to keep the hair dry
as wet hair is nearly impossible to cut
properly with clippers
start from the nape of the neck and work
your way up to the occipital bone
or the line where the head begins to
curve use a scooping motion to pull the
clippers away
don't go too high as we need to leave
room for blending
keep the consistent technique all the
way around the head
and when you reach the sides try to keep
it even about the temple area
always go against the natural direction
of the hair as this will produce
a nice clean precise cut do exactly the
same on the other side
make sure to use scooping motions as
this will guarantee
a smoother transition with the upper
portion and will be easier to blend in
afterwards the next step is to clean up
along the edges you can take the guard
attachment off now
be careful and work slowly as bear
clippers without the safety guard can be
very
sharp don't cut too much into natural
hairline
just try to trim only the edges
otherwise you will end up with white
lines
just make sure when cutting around the
ears to pull it down
to get a more accurate cut take your
time
it's always better to do this step nice
and slowly
don't forget to clean up any stray hairs
on the neck below the hairline
when cutting across the nape of the neck
be sure to stand
directly behind the person it's much
easier to make
nice straight horizontal lines
[Music]
you can even use a comb as a guide for
straight edge
remember to check both sides to make
sure they are even
you can move on to the top section i'm
going to use scissors for the top
section
so make sure to wet the hair as that
will make it much easier to cut
first you need to cut a guideline it's
an imaginary line from the forehead
to the crown the center of the head the
length you create here will determine
the way you
approach the rest of the haircut cut the
hair to the length you want between your
index and middle fingers
following the natural head shape and
moving towards crown
area leaving the hair a little bit
longer around the crown
[Music]
your guideline is now done from now on
cut in sections next to guideline to the
one side of the head
when starting a new section always take
a little bit of hair from the previously
cut
section as you can see here this is how
you will know the length to cut in the
news section
[Music]
so
move to the other side of the head and
repeat the same technique
cutting section by section make sure to
keep the hair wet when using scissors
as it will make it more easier to cut
[Music]
next blend the top into the sides i'm
going to use scissors for the blending
so make sure to wet the hair as that
will make it much easier to cut
i will show the blending with scissors
technique lift the hair out
at a 90 degree angle and hold it between
your index
and middle fingers make sure to keep the
fingers vertical
you can see a little bit of the clipped
hair below and the longer hair above it
hold the scissors vertically and cut the
longer hair off to get smooth blending
[Music]
repeat the process gradually trimming
down the longer top hair
till it blends in with the shorter
clipped hair be careful and cut a little
bit less than needed
instead repeat the process to acquire
the desired length
if you prefer you can use hair clippers
for blending
check my other videos for clipper over
comb technique
next trim the bangs combing the hair
forward
use the point cutting technique in order
to get nicely texturized fangs
positioning the scissors sideways to
achieve the proper angled cuts
but remember wet hair shortens as it
dries
so be careful not to cut too much
next styling and finishing firstly
be sure to comb out all loose hair and
trimmings
dry the hair thoroughly with a hair
dryer if you don't have a hair dryer
use a towel finish the look by using
your preferred hair styling product
[Music]
thank you so much for watching i hope
you enjoyed this haircut tutorial
and maybe learn something new make sure
to leave any questions in the comments
below
and give this video a big thumbs up if
you found it helpful
remember to subscribe and click the
notification bell to be notified when i
post
new content thanks for watching join us
again for more tutorials
[Music]